# STEADY SUPPLY LTD

Ben M. Corser

## 07933172768 ben@steady.supply https://bmcorser.github.io/

#### Statement

I am a data engineer and application developer with over 7 years professional experience. My current focus is the creation of web applications and data management systems using Unix, PostgreSQL, Python and related technology. I am an experienced programmer and have a high level of familiarity with the library ecosystems for my languages. I specialise in rapid prototyping to answer questions early, but also have a good awareness of devops concerns and am comfortable writing production-ready code. I am a friendly person with a can-do attitude and an inquiring mind. I enjoy finding solutions to difficult and unusual problems whilst writing tested, terse, readable, efficient code. I am up front and honest, but not dogmatic in my technical opinions. I write a technical blog and contribute to open source.

#### Skills

oranic -					
Programming la	anguages	Front end web development			
Python	Advanced	7 years	(X)HTML	Advanced	9 years
C++	Beginner	2 years	AJAX	Advanced	7 years
JavaScript	Advanced	9 years	OPA/SPA	Intermediate	5 years
SQL	Intermediate	8 years	Angular	Intermediate	2 years
Bash	Intermediate	7 years	Vue.js	Advanced	2 years
NodeJS/ES6	Intermediate	3 years	Vuex	Intermediate	2 years
Rust	Beginner	2 years	Webpack	Intermediate	2 years
Elm	Beginner	2 years	Require.js	Advanced	5 years
Haskell	Learner		Mocha, Chai	Advanced	4 years
			Lodash	Advanced	5 years
Asynchronous	messaging		Durandal	Intermediate	2 years
AMQP (RabbitMQ		3 years	Elm architecture	Learner	
ZeroMQ	Beginner	1 year			
	,		Back end web	development	
Container techi	nology		Django	Advanced	7 years
Docker	Intermediate	3 years	Pyramid	Advanced	5 years
LXC	Beginner	1 year	Celery	Advanced	7 years
	,	,	Flask	Advanced	7 years
Operating syste	ems		Bottle	Intermediate	2 years
Ubuntu Linux	Advanced	9 years	Klein	Beginner	1 year
Arch Linux	Intermediate	2 years	Huey	Advanced	3 years
Mac OS X	Intermediate	5 years			
mac 05 X	memediate	5 years	Data processing and machine learning		
Storage and da	ıtahase		SQLAlchemy	Advanced	7 years
PostgreSQL	Advanced	6 years	Alembic	Advanced	5 years
MySQL	Intermediate	6 years	Pandas	Intermediate	6 years
MongoDB	Advanced	3 years	Bowtie	Intermediate	2 years
CouchDB	Beginner	1 year	Sklearn	Beginner	2 years
Redis	Advanced	5 years	Hadoop	Beginner	2 years
Memcached	Intermediate	2 years	Spark	Intermediate	1 year
Cassandra	Beginner	1 year			
Cassariara	Degiririei	i yeai			

## **Project history**

## September 2017 - Dept. of International Trade (2 weeks), public sector

Short project to update libraries and provide some consultancy for internal systems. See June 2017 engagement for more information.

Stack: Docker, Postgres, Redis, ElasticSearch, Jenkins, CircleCI, Python, gunicorn, SQLAlchemy, py.test

## June 2017 until August 2017 - Grow Software (3 months), a 3D-printing startup

Expansion of previous project with permissions model (based on Unix permissions) and and real-time "push" updates to the browser using Websockets.

**Stack**: JavaScript, NodeJS, RequireJS, Websockets, Karma, Mocha, CasperJS

#### Feb 2017 until April 2017 - Cubik Labs (3 months), data visualisation startup

Service exposing results of Spark aggregations over IOT metrology data as a web API. Replication of DSE stack for infra tests, aggregation of data residing in a Cassandra database using PySpark, synchronised with Python RQ and persisted using SQLAlchemy in a Postgres database for retrieval by the web service.

Stack: Heroku, Docker, Datastax Enterprise, PySpark, Alembic, SQLAlchemy, Python RQ, NodeJS

#### July 2016 until Feb 2017 - Dept. of International Trade (8 months), public sector

Simple TFIDF project for matching companies with potential overseas opportunities to demonstrate possibilities presented by machine learning. Prototype followed by production ETL and synchronisation layer to allow a Django app to use a heavily customised MS Dynamics 2011 instance as a datastore. Front end test suite written using CasperJS forming end-to-end tests of the system.

**Stack:** AWS, Flynn, Heroku, Docker, Postgres, Redis, ElasticSearch, Jenkins, CircleCI, Python, gunicorn, SQLAlchemy, Huey, Pyramid, Sklearn, Pandas, py.test, JavaScript, CasperJS, VueJS, Mocha

#### June 2016 until August 2016 - Grow Software (3 months), a 3D-printing startup

Short project to deliver a NodeJS client for MongoDB with browser component, allowing AngularJS framework users to access remote datastore. The project was unit tested with Mocha and E2E tested using CasperJS. **Stack**: JavaScript, NodeJS, ES6, RequireJS, Karma, Mocha, CasperJS

#### Feb 2014 until June 2016 - Desktop Genetics (2 years), a bioinformatics startup

Design and implementation of data processing pipeline optimising publicly available genomic data for our application. Setting up and maintaining systems for continuous integration, configuration management, automated deployment. Low-level code and web API for genome search and scoring algorithms. Mentoring front end developers; implementing web front end allowing non-technical staff to deploy developer code to test servers for QA; genome explorer GUI allowing users to browse genomes at transcript and basepair level, with annotations and translations; implementing web API for CRUD operations; domain-specific web API (for genomic data, hence range queries, etc).

**Stack:** AWS, GCP, Digital Ocean, Hetzner, SaltStack, Ubuntu, PostgreSQL, Redis, nginx, uwsgi, Buildbot, C/C++, Python, SQAlchemy, Alembic, Celery, Huey, Pyramid, AngularJS, RequireJS, KnockoutJS, Durandal, Vue.js

#### Feb 2012 until Feb 2014 - Rockabox (2 years), high-volume ad serving system

Overhaul of reporting system from MySQL and Django ORM to PostgreSQL and SQLAlchemy, allowing the implementation of an "expression graph" query builder GUI. I was allowed to open source some of this code: <a href="https://github.com/bmcorser/expr">https://github.com/bmcorser/expr</a>

Stack: AWS, Chef, Ubuntu, MySQL, Hadoop, Hive, PostgreSQL, Redis, Python, Pandas, Numpy, SQLAlchemy

**2010 - Early projects (2 years)** Reed Foundation, LOVEFiLM, Spike Island, Works Projects, Gravitywell Various smaller projects including a web-based library loans system, an internal blogging system and a donation matching system.

## Qualifications

**2019 BSc Mathematics** Birkbeck College, London

2009 BA Fine Arts (First Class) UWE, Bristol2004 A-levels in Mathematics and Graphic Design

## Security clearance

**Security Check (SC)** <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/security-vetting-and-clearance#applicant">https://www.gov.uk/guidance/security-vetting-and-clearance#applicant</a> "determines that a person's character and personal circumstances are such that they can be trusted to work in a position which involves long-term, frequent and uncontrolled access to SECRET assets"

**Disclosure Scotland Standard** <a href="https://www.mygov.scot/standard-disclosure/">https://www.mygov.scot/standard-disclosure/</a>